

Simon Weiss Front-End Developer

## **About Me**

# Simon Weiss Traubenstraße 6

71083 Herrenberg Married / 1 daughter

0049/1725480637 hello@simon-weiss.com

Portfolio: www.simon-weiss.com

I am a Front-End Developer with experience in building web apps with JavaScript & Angular. You can find my projects that include responsive websites and games in my public porftolio. I started coding with some fun websites for myself. It turned out that the structured approach to problem solving is something I am good at and I enjoy. So I decided to learn professional coding at a software development school in Germany. Now I am looking forward to building on my experience and starting my career in IT in a junior developer position.

#### Main Stack:

- JavaScript
- TypeScript, Angular
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

#### Side Stack:

- Git, APIs (REST), Google Firebase, Scrum

# Skills

- Building Applications with JavaScript & Angular: I built landing-pages and several web apps as well as OOP-based Jump-and-Run-Games with the respective technologies.
- Working in a Software-Team: I did several group projects where I learned how to develop a software project in a team using Github.
- **High sense of responsibility:** I am used to take responsibility of my work. I always handle things like they belong to myself, so I can push the best possible result out of me.
- Doing the hard work: Beside family and working full time in my current job, I improve my professional coding skills every evening until night.
- **Learning new things:** I like challenges and improvements of my person in all fields, also if it gets hard or if it's no fun.

—

# **Professional Experience**

### **Vhf Camfacture AG / Industrial Mechanic**

JAN 2018 - PRESENT, Ammerbuch

- Developing a hightech CNC machine in a team
- Daily feedback exchange with the Technical Supervisor
- Problem solving

#### Kamafari Surfcamp Bali / Owner

DEC 2010 - DEC 2017, Uluwatu / Bali

- Building the Surfcamp from scratch
- Responsible for more than 500 guests every year
- Responsible for 15 employees
- A not payable life experience

Since Corona the Surfcamp is only a private home, my focus is now 100% on my career in IT.

#### Mercedes Benz / Industrial Mechanic

SEP 2004 - NOV 2010, Stuttgart

I started to work at the development center Trucks in Stuttgart. I was responsible to build the test stations and try different gears in long and short term tests.

# **Education**

# **Developer Akademie / JavaScript & Angular Web Development**Training

JAN 2022 - SEP 2022, Munich

Project based coding academy. Main Stack: JavaScript, Angular

Portfolio: www.simon-weiss.com

Extensive Coding School, Learning Front-End Development, Coding, Agile Project Management and building several projects in teams and alone.

#### Mercedes Benz / Industrial Mechanic

SEP 2001 - SEP 2004, Stuttgart

# Languages

German: native

English: good

Indonesian: good